Hi, my name's Jill Weiss and I'm going to give you a few tips on how to throw a curve ball in slow pitch.
First thing that you want to remember is the pitch.
Depending on the batter, if they're left handed or right handed, you always want the curve ball to kind of go away from the batter.
This kind of, especially when you're ahead of the count, this is something different that pitchers can throw to finish that out or get them to have an easy grounder, a pop up, or strike out.
So for instance, if I have a left handed batter up, I'm going to find the seams of the ball.
I don't want to be too deep into my palm, but comfortable and loose to where I can turn the ball.
One scenario I can use is turning the doorknob.
Actually spinning my wrist to have that downward motion with the ball.
Now the opposite, if I was going to have a right handed batter, I'm going to slice it underneath, okay, to get that spin this way.
So on a left handed batter, you're going to turn that knob and it's going to go away from the batter.
My name's Jill Weiss, and those are just a few tips on how to throw a curve ball in slow pitch.